# SRUTHI S NAIR Accountant

Address: Dubai Silicon Oasis
Phone : +971 525766475
E-mail: <u>sruthisnair003@gmail.com</u>



Resourceful accounting professional with 5 years of experience in managing accounts of various industries like manufacturing, F&B, education, hotels, trading, FMCG, logistics, airways, IT, hardware and networking etc. Proficient in accounting systems, reporting and presentation of Financials. Astute financial professional with keen eye for detail and high level of integrity. Works well in large teams in corporate environments

#### **SKILLS**

- Proficient in using accounting software and programs (Tally ERP, Tally Prime, QuickBooks, Xero, Microsoft Dynamics, Dolphin, Sage ERP, Zoho, ERP, Xero, SAP, Microsoft office).
- Strong interpersonal, communication & presentation skills with flexible attitude to work.
- ❖ Ability to meet a constant stream of deadlines.
- ❖ Well-versed in establishing and maintaining long-term relationships.
- Self-motivated with good analytical and problem-solving skills.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# Ethics Plus Public Accountants - (Dubai, UAE)- JAN 2023- Present

- > UAE VAT registration, de-registration, return filing, vat reconciliation and related queries
- > Conducted client interviews to collect data and information on current financial practices and areas of improvement.
- Reviewed client financial statements and data to identify risks and opportunities for improvement.
- Assists in the preparation of monthly management reports and accompanying schedules, worksheets, and narratives, including budget reports.
- Maintains all payroll operations systematically according to company policies and procedures
- > Cash flow analysis and shifts the funds as needed to maintain liquidity requirements
- Responsible for accurate and timely monthly, quarterly and year-end close.

#### UHY JAMES CHARTERED ACCOUNTANTS - (Dubai, UAE)- FEB 2021- JAN 2023

- > Prepares financial statements of the entity and conducts analysis for streamlining costs and funding revenue-generating programs.
- Prepared monthly, quarterly, interim and annual forecasts for the company including the budgeting for the year.
- Reconciling accounts receivable and accounts payable ledgers with customer and supplier statements, including circulating account statements to customers and suppliers when needed.
- ➤ Coordinate for physical stock-taking and review of differences, analysis of financial statements with valuable recommendations.

#### VBV & Assosciates - (KOCHI, INDIA)- DEC 2017- NOV 2020

- Managed statutory year-end accounts, completing client audits with thorough appraisal and communication
- > Draft Audit reports for review by the lead auditor and senior managers
- Assists in the training and coaching of junior member staff
- ➤ GST Registration and GST filing
- Preparation and Finalization of Financial Statements of Companies as per Schedule III of the Companies Act,2013
- Preparation and year-end finalization of Financial Statements of partnership firms

# **EDUCATION**

#### **❖** MBA: Finance (2020)

Institute of Chartered Financial Analysts of India

#### **❖** Post Graduate Diploma : Strategic Finance (2019)

Institute of Chartered Financial Analysts of India

# **❖** Diploma: Management (2018)

Institute of Chartered Financial Analysts of India

# **❖** CA INTERMEDIATE (2018)

The Institute of Chartered Accountants of India - India

#### Certificate in Business Basics (2018)

Institute of Chartered Financial Analysts of India - India

#### **❖** B.com Graduate: Taxation & Finance (2016)

Bishop Moore College - India

#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth: 29th January 1995

Nationality: Indian
Marital Status: Married
Visa Status: Employment